roberthalf.com 2019-05-31

# Privacy Policy | Robert Half

Last Updated: December 6, 2018

Welcome to [www.roberthalf.com](http://www.roberthalf.com/) or the Robert Half Direct mobile application (the " **Site** "). This privacy policy (" **Policy** ") describes how Robert Half International Inc. and its subsidiaries ("We", "we", "us" or "Robert Half") may use and disclose information that we may collect about you through the Site.

## Collection and Use of Personal Information

When you use or register with the Site, we may collect certain “ **Personal Information** ,” which is information that identifies you as an individual or relates to an identifiable individual. The categories of Personal Information we may collect include: your name and contact information (email, address and phone number), your job search criteria and preferences, your employment experience, educational history, your skills, reference information, background information, other information contained in your resume, or any login ID or email address and password created by you. By providing your mobile phone number to us, you opt in and consent to receive text messages from us, which includes but is not limited to text messages sent through an automatic telephone dialing system. Consent to receive marketing text messages is not required as a condition of purchasing any services from us. If you do not wish to receive marketing text messages, do not provide us with your mobile phone number.

We use Personal Information to register you with the Site, to provide you with information regarding employment opportunities and career-related information, and to otherwise provide you with requested information or services. We may from time to time use your Personal Information to send you automated email messages, text messages (message and data rates may apply), or marketing materials regarding our services, including employment information. We may also use Personal Information for our business purposes, such as data analysis, audits, and improving our services.

## Disclosures of Personal Information

Robert Half may disclose Personal Information to third parties in the following circumstances: (1) to our third-party service providers who perform business functions and services on our behalf; (2) to comply with applicable laws, the service of legal process, or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law requiring such disclosure; (b) protect the rights or property of Robert Half or its affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of the users or the public. We also may disclose or transfer information to a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).

## Collection and Use of Other Information

“ **Other Information** ” is any information that does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an identifiable individual.

We may collect Other Information in a variety of ways, including:

If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, most browsers allow you to automatically decline cookies, or be given the choice of declining or accepting a particular cookie (or cookies) from a particular site. If, however, you do not accept cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of the Site.

  * **Through your browser or device:** Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, and Internet browser type and version. We use this information to ensure that the Site functions properly.
  * **Using cookies:** Cookies are pieces of information stored on the computer that you are using. Cookies allow us to collect information such as browser type, time spent on the Site, pages visited, registrations, submissions, demographics, information requests, language preferences, and other traffic data. We use the information for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively, and to personalize your experience. We also gather statistical information about use of the Site to enhance its functionality, understand how it is used and assist us with resolving questions about it. We may also use cookies and other technologies in online advertising campaigns to track responses to our ads.
  * **Using pixel tags and other similar technologies:** Pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) may be used to, among other things, track the actions of Site users and email recipients, market our services to you, measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about Site usage and response rates.
  * **Analytics:** We use third-party analytics providers such as Google Analytics and Inspectlet on the Site. Google Analytics uses cookies and similar technologies to collect and analyze information about use of the Services and report on activities and trends. Google Analytics may also collect information regarding the use of other websites, apps and online resources. You can learn about Google’s practices by going to [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites), and opt out by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at [ https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). We have also engaged Inspectlet to analyze the activities of visitors to this Site, and Inspectlet’s authorized use of cookies and other tracking technologies enable it to have access to Personal Information of visitors to this Site. Such access to and use of Personal Information by Inspectlet is governed by Inspectlet’s privacy policy, available at <https://www.inspectlet.com/legal#privacy>.
  * **IP address:** Your IP Address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider. An IP Address may be identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user accesses the Site, along with the time of the visit and the pages visited. We use IP Addresses for purposes such as calculating usage levels, diagnosing server problems, and administering the Site. We may also derive your approximate location from your IP Address.

Please note that we may use and disclose Other Information for our business purposes.

## Retargeting

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads regarding our services when you access and use other websites, based on information relating to your use of the Site. To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through use of pixel tags). By utilizing the Site, you consent to the use of cookie or other tracking technologies to serve you retargeted advertising. Data collected may be shared with our third party vendor Criteo for cross device linking and advertising purposes. If you would like to learn more about cross device linking or opt out of Criteo advertising, please visit <http://www.criteo.com/privacy/>.

If you would like more information about opting out of this advertising in desktop and mobile browsers on the particular device on which you are accessing this Policy or this type of advertising, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> and <http://www.aboutads.info/>.

## Third Party Services

This Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site or service to which the Site links.

## Security

We use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures designed to protect Personal Information within our organization. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please immediately notify us in accordance with the “Contacting Us” section below.

## Choices

If you no longer want to receive marketing-related emails from us on a going-forward basis, you may opt-out by using the mechanism contained in each such email.

## SMS Terms

If you no longer wish to receive candidate/job matches or job status updates from us on a going-forward basis, you may opt-out by texting “STOP” to us at any time. You may text “HELP” to us or call 1.800.803.9336 for assistance relating to text messages we send. For more information, you may also text "HELP" to short code 37938.

## Use of Site by Minors

The Site is not directed to individuals under the age of eighteen (18) and we do not knowingly collect Personal Information from individuals under 18. If you are a resident of California, under 18 and a registered user of the Site, you may ask us to remove content or information that you have posted to the Site by writing to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#a6d1c3c4cbc7d5d2c3d4e6d4c9c4c3d4d2cec7cac088c5c9cb). Please note that your request does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information, as, for example, some of your content may have been reposted by another user.

## Jurisdictional Issues

The Site is controlled and operated by us from the United States and is not intended to subject us to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of the United States.

## Revisions to the Policy

If we change this Policy we will post any updates here for your review. The “Last Updated” line at the top of this page indicates when this Policy was last revised. Any changes will become effective when we post the revised Policy on the Site. Your use of the Site following these changes means that you accept the revised Policy.

## Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this website privacy policy, or if you would like to update any personal information you have provided to us, please contact us at:

Mailing Address:

The Webmaster 

Robert Half International Inc. 

2884 Sand Hill Road 

Suite 200

Menlo Park, California 94025

Email Address: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#3d4a585f505c4e49584f7d4f525f584f49555c515b135e5250)

## Availability Status

Let us know you're ready to work with one click.

## Set Your Status

Click the blue button on your profile page at least once a week to keep your status set to Available.

## Set Your Status

Your status will automatically change to Idle and Unknown over time, so update it weekly while you’re looking for work
